♪ In the not too
distant future ♪
♪ Next Sunday, A.D. ♪
♪ There was a guy named Joel ♪
♪ Not too different
from you or me ♪
♪ He worked at
Gizmotic Institute ♪
♪ Just another face
in a red jumpsuit ♪
♪ He did a good job
cleaning up the place ♪
♪ But his bosses
didn't like him ♪
♪ So they shot him into space ♪
♪ We'll send him cheesy movies ♪
♪ The worst we can find ♪
♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ He'll have to sit
and watch them all ♪
♪ And we'll monitor his mind ♪
♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ Now keep in mind
Joel can't control ♪
♪ Where the movies
begin or end ♪
♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ Because he used
those special parts ♪
♪ To make his robot friends ♪
♪ Robot roll call ♪
♪ All right, let's go ♪
♪ Cambot ♪
♪ Pan left ♪
♪ Gypsy ♪
♪ Hi girl ♪
♪ Tom Servo ♪
♪ What a cool guy ♪
♪ Crow ♪
♪ He's a wise cracker ♪
♪ If you're wondering how
he eats and breathes ♪
♪ And other science facts ♪
♪ La, la, la ♪
♪ Then repeat to yourself,
it's just a show ♪
♪ I should really just relax ♪
♪ For Mystery Science
Theater 3000 ♪
(mysterious music)
(audience applauding)
- Cambot, you don't have to
put applause in now, okay.
But you could bring
it in a little bit.
Go ahead.
Come on in.
A little bit more.
That's good, okay.
People of Earth,
my name is Joel and I'm
marooned in outer space.
- [Announcer] Commercial
starting in 15 seconds.
- I'm the subject of a bizarre
movie watching experiment,
and now, I guess, so are you.
I'm expecting a
call any second now
from the two evil scientists
who shot me into space
for no good reason at all.
- [Announcer] Commercial
starting in five, four,
three, two, commercial
starting now.
(Joel hitting button)
- Stick around.
We'll be right back.
(upbeat music)
- You know, one of
the really hard things
about being marooned
in outer space
is you start to miss
the little things
that you have
every day on Earth,
you know, like rain, and
snow, and mini marshmallows.
You know, that's why
these vacuum flowers
are important to me.
They're like the only living,
oh, I'm being called by
my two evil overlords.
- Come in, Joel, mate, my
spunky little space sock.
- Hey sirs, what's going on?
- It's time for the
invention exchange.
What have you got
for us, skanky boy?
- Yeah, I got this
new thing here.
It's a, looks like an
ordinary circular saw,
but it's actually a safety saw.
See, it's got a
little infrared light
that senses when your
appendages or fingers are near,
it shuts itself
off automatically.
(saw cranking)
I'll show you what I mean.
(saw whirring)
(Joel screaming)
I'm just kidding, it's a trick.
Fake fingers.
- Oh yes, we knew that.
Well, it's our turn
for our little experimental
house party this week, Joel.
- Okay, say you want
to emulate Reed Richard
from the Fantastic Four,
and you need a longer
arm to reach something
or change the channel,
just use our limb
lengthener here.
- Yes, just select
the appropriate limb.
In this case, Larry's
volunteered his arm.
Comfy?
(Larry grunting)
Yes, all right.
And just stretch away.
(Larry yelping and groaning)
Oh it doesn't hurt that
much, you whiny little baby.
(Larry grunting)
- Well, I have a feeling
you're probably violating
somebody's basic human
rights, namely Dr. Erhardt's.
- [Both] Thank you.
- Well, speaking of violations,
here's a little
cinematic intrusion,
called The Crawling Hand.
- It has a star from
Gilligan's Island,
and one from The Big Valley,
and one the Hamburger
Helper commercial.
- Yes.
(both grunting)
- Enjoy.
- Oh brother.
(alarm buzzing)
Movie sign.
(mysterious music)
- [Tom] The Crawling Hand.
Hey Joel.
- [Joel] Hi.
- [Crow] How'd the
scientists like your deal?
- [Joel] Okay.
They're crazier than
ever though, you know.
- [Crow] Yeah.
- [Tom] They're kind of
dickweeds, aren't they?
- [Joel] You could say that.
(mysterious music)
- [Tom] This is like
Love, American Style.
- [Crow] Hey, Alan Hale,
isn't that The Skipper?
- [Joel] Yeah.
Little Buddy.
I can see my house
from here, you guys.
- [Crow] Hey, Joel, did
they do these titles
on a typewriter?
- [Joel] No, that's the
helvetica constellation
we're looking at.
- [Crow] Oh.
Stellar.
- [Tom] Is Artie Shaw in this?
- [Joel] No, I don't think so.
- [Crow] Just off camera.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] (groaning) Scary.
(Crow moaning)
- [Lockhart] Do you read me?
Do you read me?
- [Tom] Like a book.
- [Lockhart] Someone,
please, come in.
Oh my god.
- [Joel] It's Kirk Douglas.
- [Tom] Anytown, USA.
- [Announcer] Dr. Weitzberg,
contact range officer.
Paging system now secured
for emergency use only.
- [Crow] Unless you have
a note from your parents.
- [Announcer] 46 hours,
20 minutes, zero seconds.
- [Crow] Boy, he
really needs a smoke.
- Space Operations,
Florida division.
Hold on.
It's the press.
- [Tom] Tell 'em I'm smoking.
- What do we tell them, Steve?
- I'll tell you
what to tell 'em.
- [Tom] Tell 'em I'm smoking.
- Tell 'em we sent our
second man to the moon.
Looks like he's not
coming back either.
Oh, I'm sorry Donna, I
shouldn't have said that.
- [Crow] Oops.
- [Tom] I'm sorry.
Just tell 'em I'm smoking.
He's smoking.
- We can release no
statement at this time.
- Oxygen countdown.
- Mr. Curan would like a
countdown on the oxygen,
every 15 seconds.
- [Crow] And an ashtray.
- [Announcer] Two
minutes, 30 seconds.
- No contact for
nine full hours.
(chair crashing)
- [Tom] Goll.
- [Crow] Get him some decaf.
- Same thing all over again.
- [Joel] Too many years
at the Strasberg school.
- Same thing all over again.
- [Joel] Isn't that Nick
from The Big Valley?
- [Crow] Yeah.
- Yet the whole rigs
clicking like a dream.
- [Announcer] Two
minutes, 15 seconds.
- [Tom] And 62 bottles
of beer on the wall.
- We licked every problem.
Put a man on the moon.
No, we got him off.
Everything worked fine,
but Lockhart.
What happened to him?
- [Announcer] Two minutes,
zero seconds.
(phone buzzing)
- Mr. Curan's desk.
Yes, sir, one moment.
- [Tom] He's smoking.
- White House.
- [Crow] Tell him I'm smoking.
- No, not now.
No.
- [Joel] No self
respecting scientist
would have his shirt
unbuttoned that far.
I'm sorry.
- Mr. Curan feels
certain that there's
no hope for Captain Lockhart.
Yes, sir.
- [Tom] Plus he's smoking.
- [Joel] Isn't that
a David Bowie song?
- [Crow] I hate cappuccino.
- [Announcer] One
minute, 30 seconds.
- [Tom] Hey, scientists
shouldn't litter.
- You all right?
- [Tom] Shut up and
throw the cup away.
- [Announcer] One minute.
- How's our boss holding up?
- [Tom] He's probably smoking.
- As usual he's not said a word.
- I wouldn't get too close
to him if I were you.
- [Crow] Yeah, his breath
could stop a Titan missile.
- I was figuring on
giving him a sedative.
- [Tom] Funny.
- [Joel] Hey, they all
got stripes in their hair.
- [Crow] Yeah, it looks like
land of the skunk people.
- [Tom] Hair styles
by Gordon of Gotham.
- Will be in about 60 seconds.
Well,
we've done it your way twice.
- Well now, we don't pretend
to know all the answers.
- Apparently no one does.
- [Tom] Except for her.
- For every frontier
that's been explored.
- [Announcer] 45 seconds.
- Men have died.
We've only lost two men on
the strangest frontier of all.
- [Tom] Cable.
- There are millions of people
in this world, Dr. Weitzberg,
but there are only four men left
who can handle the lunar rocket.
- [Joel] The Beatles?
- [Tom] And her.
- We've lost one-third
of the men we have.
It's like a conveyor
to oblivion.
- [Crow] Like your career.
- [Announcer] 30 seconds.
- The situation that happened
to those first two men
was not only duplicated,
but widely exaggerated
in their training.
- Those men did not
have a mental crack up.
I'd stake my life on it.
- There is no duplicate
for the solitude of space.
If those men could've looked
in their viewing screen
and seen two, three,
or more sister ships
alongside out there.
- 15 seconds.
- They wouldn't have panicked!
- [Tom] Bang.
- [Crow] Ow.
- You heard those tapes.
Those men did not panic!
- [Crow] Why are they shouting?
- Nine, eight
seven.
- The remaining four men.
- [Tom] Seven seconds
till he slaps the table.
- [Announcer] Five, four.
- Do it without me.
- [Tom] Four, three, two, one.
- [Announcer] Zero.
Oxygen depleted.
- [Tom] Slap table.
(slapping table)
Thank you.
- I'll see you in
Washington, tomorrow.
- [Tom] I'm going
to get some air.
(Donna crying)
- [Crow] Hey, she's making
that loon call with her hands.
(Crow whistling)
- [Joel] Cool, Steve,
did you ever think about
getting your hair frosted?
- Steve.
- [Joel] I don't you
have a widow's peak now.
- Think he knew about
Donna and Mel Lockhart?
- I don't know, Doc.
If he did, I doubt it
would make much difference.
- [Tom] Let's see, you
mess with this switch,
twist that, flip this.
Oh, someone's coming.
Good luck with
that. (snickering)
- Well, Steve, might as well
write our formal (mumbling).
- I can't take much
more of this, Doc.
- [Crow] Yeah, soon
I'll have to move off
of the corner of this formica.
- No he can justify it.
- Oh, our boss is Secretary
of Space Operation,
and that cabinet
post entitles him
to be a very daring man.
- No, we got to stop him, Doc.
- All right, Steve, before
you go see him tomorrow
stop by my office.
- [Joel] I'll give
you a protein rinse.
- I don't get it.
I just don't get it!
The pattern is the
same as before.
Perfect takeoff, clear
contact all the way,
perfect landing.
You heard Lockhart when he
was on the lunar surface.
Liftoff from the moon, perfect.
One hour later, nothing,
and we had him right here, Doc.
- [Tom] Sure wish I had
that command of my arms.
- If he wanted to talk to us,
he didn't have to
push a lousy button.
- [Tom] Look at
that fluid motion.
- [Lockhart] Do you read me?
Do you read me?
Lockhart, X20,
approaching ionosphere.
- [Tom] Hey, someone
screwed up all the knobs.
- Someone please come in.
- [Joel] Max Hedroom's dad.
(machine whirring)
- [Joel] And the music
goes round and round
and it comes out here.
- [Crow] Hey, it's a spirograph.
- X20 to moon lab.
Do you read me?
- Lockhart, this is moon lab.
Curan, Steve Curan.
Come in X20.
- Steve.
- [Tom] Look, it's
Tammy Faye Bakker.
- It's coming on again.
- [Joel] Yeah, he looks
more like Robert Smith
from The Cure.
- My god, my god,
Kill, kill!
- [Crow] Looks like
he needs the cure.
- What's wrong with that man?
- I don't know, Steve.
This is Doc Weitzberg.
How long have you
been without oxygen?
- 15, maybe 20 minutes.
- That's impossible.
- Why did you break contact?
- [Lockhart] (mumbling)
contact, please.
Kill, no, no, don't.
Steve, I can't make it.
Lost control.
- [Tom] Have you considered
frosting your hair?
- [Lockhart] Push the red.
- He can't push that red
button, it'll blow him up.
- [Tom] Push the red button.
- I can't make it.
- [Crow] I think he's
taken acting lessons
from William Shatner.
- [Lockhart] Something
makes my arm move.
Makes me do things.
Kill, kill!
- [Tom] This is Major
Tom to Ground Control.
- [Lockhart] I'm 200000 feet.
Push the red.
Something end.
- Why do you want us to push it?
You can push it if you want to.
- [Joel] It's better
when you push it.
- [Lockhart] I
can't move my arms.
Kill, kill!
- [Tom] Looks like the
DOW's up about three points.
- Push the red.
No more time.
- What's his position?
Where is he?
- Inland.
Populated area of California.
- 140000.
Push the red!
- [Tom] Must push button.
- My god, my god.
God, Steve, help me, help me!
- [Tom] Well he
still has good teeth.
- [Lockhart] The red.
- [Joel] Here, I'll push it.
Let me be the one.
I want to push this thing.
- 70000.
Push it!
- [Crow] Push that
and he's an astro-not.
(Lockhart screaming)
(spaceship exploding)
(upbeat music)
- [Lockhart] My god.
God, Steve, help me.
Help me!
Push the red.
70000.
- [Joel] Sounds like
my old Phy Ed teacher,
push it.
Push it.
- [Lockhart] Push it!
- [Crow] And then
the tape ran out.
But we've got it on CD too.
- Well, that's one tape we
don't want Donald to transcribe.
- Don't worry, I'll
take care of it.
- [Tom] It's pretty morbid
to keep listening to that.
- How can a man continue
to function without oxygen
for 20 minutes?
- He can't.
- Lockhart did.
So we know something
kept him functioning.
- A substitute for oxygen?
- [Tom] New oxygen light.
- I don't know Steve.
But ever since we lost Nelson,
an idea's been buzzing around
in my brain like a fly.
A very persistent fly.
(Crow buzzing)
- After hearing Lockhart
the buzzing stops.
You know, I think
I've hit on something.
Want it hear it out then?
- Go ahead.
Have at it.
- Well I think what kept
Lockhart going was life.
An independent, vital force.
Something living.
- [Crow] Oh, and I suppose
next you'll tell me
there's rings around Uranus.
- Well living covers a
lot of territory, Steve.
And I don't think Lockhart
was alone on his return flight
anymore than Nelson was.
- Well now.
- (laughing) I'm not
talking about the three men.
As a matter of fact,
I may not talk at all,
unless I get some encouragement.
- Well, what do you need?
A drink maybe?
- [Joel] What, are
you coming on to me?
- And you're the one
that can get Berringer
to give it to me.
- Time?
For what?
- Time to prove that this
force, this new life,
was born on the X20.
- Go ahead.
- I need you with me
all the way, Steve.
- [Crow] He asked
me, he asked me.
- I am with you.
- What makes life?
A certain particular
combination of molecules
or carbon or
silicons or nitrogen
or any number of these things.
- [Tom] Blah, blah, blah.
- Certain temperature.
Mix well.
Call it what you will.
- [Tom] Serve over cracked ice
and garnish with a parasol.
- Swirling together
in tiny orbits,
fuses these things into a
precise energy relationship,
which we call life.
- No, wait a minute.
What you're saying is that.
- [Joel] Boy, he's slow, huh?
- Life might mutate,
or even fully evolve
in a matter of hours
or even minutes.
- [Tom] No, you're wrong.
- What happens when we
send a man up there?
- [Joel] Speed it up.
Let's go.
- We don't just send
a man in a rocket.
We send up living cells.
- [Tom] They don't (mumbling).
- [Joel] Snap out of it.
- Germs.
We throw in
radioactive (mumbling).
We introduce all
these to cosmic rays.
Do we upset this balance?
Do we start a cycle?
Does a living cell from
Earth romance a cosmic ray
and give birth to an
illegitimate monster,
who makes his nest in?
- [Tom] I wonder if
there's an abridged version
of this movie.
- [Doc] Beginning to (mumbling).
Perhaps-
- [Crow] If there
is, let's burn it.
- Be dying.
Anything evolving
so rapidly could.
- [Tom] Never burn your bridges.
- Well Steve.
- Quite a chunk.
- Oh, throw out the logic
pills when you swallow it.
This theory can't be measured
by anything we already know.
(Tom singing)
- Sounds like a good case.
- I was hoping you'd say that.
- Berringer won't.
He won't go for a theory,
even if it's true.
- Then lie to him,
but buy me the time.
- [Crow] Buy me things.
Buy me things.
(upbeat music)
- [Joel] All right.
- No dancing.
No dancing, not allowed.
No dancing.
- [Tom] What a grouch.
- [Joel] It's just
like Footloose.
- No rats, not allowed.
- [Tom] Unless
they're on the menu.
No acting, not allowed.
- And you were gonna
be a nurse, Patsy?
- Well what are you
doing with them?
- I picked them up at the
Express office for Grandpa.
They're for the lab at school.
- Well, maybe you're
grandfather's a
biology professor,
and you're boyfriend's
a premed student,
but my father's a sheriff, and
rats and the law don't mix.
- [Joel] I thought
they were synonymous.
- Voila.
No rats.
- [Tom] Good trick.
- You didn't bite.
(woman grunting)
When I said boyfriend.
- You mean Paul?
- Oh, then he isn't
just a mutual interest
in hives and chicken pox.
- He's very nice.
- But how did you hook him?
- [Crow] Rubber
frog and pork rind.
- The lone wolf they call us.
(Crow howling)
Oh, I'm not saying
you're not his type,
but he's just not with it.
- Just good friends.
- [Crow] Joel, move your head.
Thank you.
- [Joel] Yeah, looks like bud,
from My Three Sons.
- You think I'm kidding, huh?
You two see that
thing last night?
- [Joel] What, you
mean My Three Sons?
- I didn't see anything.
- Well, I phoned your father.
Why there was a fireball in
the sky as big as a house.
He didn't see it either.
- Well, what do
you think it was?
- Didn't I tell ya?
Eat, drink, and be merry,
tomorrow ya die.
- [Tom] Well, no,
wouldn't it be today,
if there was a fire
ball last night?
(women laughing)
- [Announcer] And now for
your local news, here in.
- [Crow] Hey, he's got a woody.
- [Announcer] The traffic
commission has decided.
- Hi.
- [Both] Hi Paul.
- Come on, sit down beside me.
- [Crow] Nah, I'll
sit where the rat was.
- Come on, finish your milk.
Let's get going.
- Can we stop by my house?
- What for?
It's getting late.
- I got to pick up
my bathing suit.
- But I told you
I'd meet you here.
You said you'd have
your suit with you.
- [Tom] Mr. Charm.
- I just can't get used to going
swimming at Christmas time.
- [Crow] With a suit on?
- [Patsy] Well I can
tell you one thing.
- What's that?
- It's for real.
You sound like a
married couple already.
(Paul and Marta laughing)
- Come on, finish your milk.
- [Joel] That's not milk.
That's pancake batter
she's drinking.
- [Crow] Pancake batter?
You're soaking in it.
- [Joel] Shotgun.
- Okay?
I've got to drop these at
home for Grandpa anyhow.
- Okay, let's get a move on.
- [Crow] Hey, they
packed a lunch.
- Bye Patsy.
- Goodbye you two love birds.
- [Tom] Ratatouille.
- Hey Paul.
What are they saying
over at the school
about that thing in
the sky last night?
- Well nothing, why?
Everybody said it was a meteor.
(Soda shop owner laughing)
- Hey, come on.
Don't tell me you're still
scared of them flying saucers?
- [Joel] Come on, bub, you
can't let fear run your life.
- [Crow] Yeah, pops.
- Eat, drink, and be merry.
- [Tom] Get over it.
(upbeat music)
- [Crow] Yeah, take a
lesson from these teeners.
Twist your troubles away.
- [Tom] Let's twist again,
like we did last summer, Joel.
- [Joel] Yeah.
(tires screeching)
- [Tom] Yowser.
- [Joel] Look,
it's Ed Begley Sr.
- Oh, hi children.
- Hi.
I picked this up for you
at the Express office.
- Thank you.
- Love you, Grandpa.
Gotta run.
- Hello there, Mr. Farnstrom.
- I never really
understand how you do it.
- [Tom] It's easy.
I just tie the sleeves
around my neck.
- It's 15 minutes
past the last bell,
and already you are off
somewhere with my granddaughter.
- Well, we have a system sir.
A secret system.
- Ah, secret.
- [Crow] He looks
like a cross between
Jerry Mathers and James Dean.
- [Tom] Beaver without a cause.
- (mumbling) that
you have to fail.
Do work together.
- [Tom] Joel, we got
to get out of here.
Carry me.
- Not me Professor.
When I make it, I'll
make it on my own.
All the way.
- [Crow] Oop, sorry.
I'm coming.
- What did I tell you?
(mysterious music)
(bowling pins falling)
- Hey, baby splits.
Wow, that's gonna
be tough to beat.
- [Tom] Here we are
in the fifth frame.
Crow is staring at a
nasty six-ten split.
He really needs this one.
Oh, good hook, yes.
(pins falling)
(Crow yelling)
- All right.
- Bingo!
- Great shot.
- Nice shot Crow.
- Hey, that puts
me over 120, Joel.
- All right, that was excellent!
- Ow, great game.
- These new arms
are working great.
- You know, but I hate
these rental shoes,
'cause no matter how much of
that stuff they spray into 'em,
your feet still smell funny.
- Smell, I didn't
know you could smell.
- Did I say smell?
I meant spectral
analysis, of course.
- Hey, I was thinking,
let's play murderball now.
What do you say?
- Uh, no.
- Wait a minute.
I created you guys,
so when I say we play
murderball, we play murderball.
- Okay, not it.
- Not it.
- Let's do it over.
- Well how about rock,
paper, scissors, huh?
- Oh, no way, I'm not
playing that with you again.
Look at my hands.
Look, see.
You know, every time we
play, I got to be scissors,
and you pick rock all the time.
- Hey, it's just the
luck of the draw, Crow.
Come on.
- Okay, Joel, you
win everything.
- Yeah, bye, see ya.
- See ya later, Joel.
- Go home to your mom, yeah.
We're your friends.
- [Tom and Crow] Not.
- Come on, let's ditch him.
- Oh that's great, I get it.
Yeah, yeah, thanks Joel.
Thanks for emptying my load pan.
Thanks for creating us, Joel.
Thanks for making us
intrinsically human, Joel.
Hey Cambot, come
in a little bit.
Cambot, I want you to
remind me of something.
Next time I make a
robot, no more free will.
That's it.
We got commercial.
I hate this.
(upbeat music)
(peaceful music)
(Marta giggling)
- [Tom] Ow.
- [Joel] Ouch, ooh, sting, pain.
- [Tom] Oh, oh, hot, hot.
Hot, hot, hot, hot, ow, thud.
(man grunting)
- (laughing) Are you hurt?
- (grunting) Only my pride.
- [Tom] And my lumbar.
- [Crow] He landed on it.
- Poor boy.
The sensitive male
ego, so easily wounded.
- I think I know now the secret
of how to be successful
with a woman.
- You do?
Tell me.
- You have to be weak, pathetic,
then they feel sorry for you.
- [Tom] You're all
those things, and less.
- I think you discovered it.
- I know I have.
I always wondered why
some spindly little runts
had the girls chasing after 'em.
Because they felt sorry for 'em.
- Of course.
- [Tom] And usually
they have money too.
- But you were fooling me.
You're not weak.
- Darn right.
Now I've got you.
- [Crow] Hey, is this
From Here to Eternity?
- [Tom] No, it just
seems like an eternity.
- Oh Paul.
I guess I'm not like
those other women.
I don't like weak men at all.
- Listen, will you
once and for all
give me a serious answer?
- What about?
- Are you going home, to Sweden,
after the semester's over?
- Why not?
I only planned to come
to California for a year.
To see Grandfather,
and go to an American
school for a while.
- [Tom] Meet some
football teams.
- Nothing has come up
to change my plans.
- What do you mean?
What about me?
- No.
I planned there
would be a boy too.
- [Joel] Oh, you little minx.
- [Tom] Oh no, don't throw
my shorts in the sand.
Damn you!
(Marta laughing)
All right, she's
a stripping minx.
- Don't come any closer.
I've nothing on.
- Ah, faker, you haven't
had time to undress.
- Maybe I didn't.
- [Joel] How would he know?
- But I have now.
- Okay, you win.
- [Tom] I'll accept that.
Soon to be naked is better
than not naked at all.
- You know, I don't think your
grandfather approves of me.
- [Joel] 'Cause you're naked.
- You're wrong.
He considers you the best
student in his class.
- I meant as a
member of the family.
What do I have to do,
say it in Swedish?
- [Joel] How do you
say moon in Swedish?
- [Tom] Hubba hubba.
- Paul, what does it
mean, I'm stacked?
And you're not worthy?
- Stacked?
- [Crow] Stacked means
you're really smart.
(water splashing)
- Patsy, this afternoon.
- [Crow] Hey, why's she wearing
a swimsuit with a codpiece?
- [Tom] Oh, just
for the halibut.
- Is something wrong?
- [Tom] (laughing) Sorry.
- [Crow] Stop it, you're
giving me a haddock.
- [Tom] (laughing) You're
a pain in the bass.
- [Crow] You have no sole.
(Marta mumbling)
- How do you say it in Swedish?
- Say what?
- Nothing, let's hit the water.
- You know something?
American men marry
much too young.
- You know something.
It's because of
Swedish girls like you.
- [Tom] The kind that
get naked in public.
- [Crow] Hey, last one in
the fjord's a rotten egg.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Hey, it's
a beach thermometer.
- Well, Donna, I've
called everywhere
and haven't been
able to find him.
Didn't he say
where he was going?
- No, he was quite
upset when he left.
He banged on the
typewriter for a while.
He was in a mood.
- I've got to talk
to him right away.
It's urgent
- [Joel] I need more calendars.
- He wants to be alone.
- Well this is the one
time he shouldn't be alone.
- Doc, you've got me worried.
- I didn't mean to scare you.
This is a matter of the
greatest importance.
- I'll try.
- I'll be here until
I hear from you.
Donna, everything all right?
- [Tom] Well my
collar's too tight.
- Yes Doc.
- Bye.
- Goodbye.
- [Joel] Boy, they're
good swimmers.
(Marta screaming)
- [Crow] Waders.
See the sand is hot.
- Boy, that water was cold.
- [Tom] You know what
that means? (laughing)
(Marta grunting)
- All right, now.
- [Joel] The biking,
then the marathon.
- Now what?
- The answer.
- Answer?
What answer?
- [Joel] Take it easy.
- [Crow] Sorry.
- Are you gonna stay here?
- Well why should I do that?
- So I can marry you, stupid.
- Marry me?
- [Tom] I'll marry you
stupid, smart, anyway.
(Marta giggling)
Whoa, he upended her.
Hi, I'm Tom Servo.
(Marta screaming)
- [Crow] Hey, I found my watch.
(dramatic music)
- Paul, Paul, take
me away, please.
- Sure baby, sure.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Did he just offer
his hand in marriage?
- [Tom] Well, not
exactly his hand.
- I'll lock it in
the trunk of the car.
- No, no, I couldn't stand it.
Let's go right to the sheriff.
There's been a murder.
- No, not a murder.
- A human hand not a murder.
- Listen, please.
You've just got to trust me.
If it's what I think it is,
it could be very
important for me, please.
- No, no, just take
me away from here.
- [Joel] I love her,
but I want the hand.
I still love her though.
And that hand would
be really great.
But, I don't know what.
- [Tom] Babe, hand, babe, hand.
(dramatic music)
- Put your hands
up, or I'll shoot
- Oh, Mrs. Hotchkiss,
it's only me.
- [Crow] It's Harriet
Nelson's evil twin.
- You said you wouldn't
be home until late.
- Oh, I just remembered
this old pile of papers.
I thought I'd come back
and look something up.
- Well, what'd you come
in the back door for?
You know how jumpy I am
about noises in the house.
I got Mr. Hotchkiss'
old gun out.
I thought they'd carry a
burglar out of here tonight.
- [Tom] Could I just take
one practice shot at you?
I was kinda psyched.
- I was gonna shoot,
and ask questions later.
- [Tom] Just one shot.
- It's got a hair trigger too.
Well, as long as
it's you, it's okay.
How 'bout some supper?
- Oh, no thanks.
- I have some stew left
over from last night.
I could heat it up for ya.
- No, I.
- [Crow] If the gun doesn't
kill him, the stew will.
- I'm not hungry really.
I guess I'll just go up to
my room, if you don't mind.
Good night.
- Good night.
- [Tom] Hey, come on, one shot.
I'll just wing ya.
It won't hurt that much.
- [Joel] I've got
to have that hand.
Can't eat, can't sleep.
All I do is think about it.
Maybe if there's something.
Oh, no.
- [Crow] Man, with an
extra hand around the house
just think of the
stuff I could do.
Just think.
(waves crashing)
- [Joel] Star
light, star bright,
first hand I see tonight.
I wish I may, I wish I might.
(Paul whistling)
- [Tom] Little human hand.
Come here.
Little human hand.
Come on.
Little human hand, yes.
- [Crow] If you want
to catch a human hand,
you got to think
like a human hand.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] That's giant.
That hand's unbelievably huge.
- [Crow] It's called
for shortening, Joel.
- [Joel] Cootchie cootchie coo.
Cootchie cootchie coo.
- [Tom] You got
to hand it to him.
- [Crow] Went out on
a limb with that one.
- [Joel] It's a good thing
he brought that
freezer wrap along.
- [Tom] I don't think
it's freezer wrap.
I think it's a handbag.
(Tom laughing)
- [Crow] Oh that'll go great
with a little glass
of milk later.
A little honey cured hand.
(dramatic music)
Next to the hand
cream on the shelf.
- Yeah, Steve, it's positive.
There is a reading.
- [Crow] Yes, you've
proved that they are rats.
- It was a positive reading.
This may be all the evidence
we need to convince Berringer.
- Oh, really?
- [Tom] Oh these two guys.
We're in for some
serious acting now.
- Don't you understand?
I'm giving you the answer.
- It's too late, Doc.
- What's that?
- It's my resignation.
- Oh, you talked to him?
- Oh no, not quite.
He talked.
He said either get on
his wagon, or get out.
Well I'm getting out.
- Well now, wait a minute.
Tear it up, you don't need it.
This is the gauge I've
been telling you about.
It measures the
results of cosmic rays.
Or the presence of
something associated with.
- What is the something, Doc?
- Well, I don't know,
- [Tom] It's a something.
- But I did make a very
important discovery
about Elmer here.
- Has he got it?
- Oh, very definitely.
- So how did he get it?
- [Crow] Probably
at a night club.
- Oh, I see.
You're not aware of Elmer.
He's a very distinguished rat.
- [Joel] Perhaps you're
familiar with his glue.
- He was a passenger on
our last space program,
before we launched our
first manned rocket.
In the beginning we thought
he was completely unaffected.
- But he wasn't?
- [Joel] I think the doctor's
been spending a little too
much time in the rat lab.
- I don't know when he'll
turn on the other rats
and kill 'em.
Now he can unlock
an ordinary cage.
That's why I had that
padlock put on there.
Everyone else around
here seems to think that
what he does isn't in the range
of an exceptional
rat's capabilities.
But I don't.
I think Elmer has thoughts.
- [Tom] Naughty thoughts.
- [Joel] Human thoughts.
- Are they human?
- [Tom] Better than
human thoughts.
- Like this something.
The same something
that was in our pilots.
- Well Steve, there's
a possibility.
(paper ripping)
(upbeat music)
(dramatic music)
(bottles clanking)
- [Tom] It's W.C. Handy.
(light switch clicking)
- [Crow] Hey, she's
wearing a drool pad.
- [Joel] She's putting on
Dr. Spock's house coat.
- [Tom] Doctor or mister?
- [Joel] Mister.
- [Crow] Dr. Mister?
- [Tom] Mr. Mister.
- [Joel] Mr. Misdemeanor.
- [Tom] That's what you get
when you rob a
Dairy Queen, right?
- [Crow] Wow, she's pretty
quick with that cold steel.
- [Joel] Nuts in her girdle.
- [Tom] Good thing
she has a handgun.
Cujo?
- [Joel] Hey boy.
- [Crow] Hey, come
on, this isn't funny.
- [Tom] Guys?
Guys?
- [Crow] Don't take that off.
Your chin'll explode.
- Jackson.
Have you been making
this noise out here?
Come on, get down.
You know better than that.
(cat meowing)
- [Crow] Oops, sorry
Jackson, was that your head?
- What is this doing out here?
(cat meowing)
- [Tom] Just kinda lying there.
(light switch clicking)
(cat meowing)
- Oh, what a mess.
- [Joel] A chocolate mess.
- That boy.
(gun clattering)
(cat meowing)
He said he wasn't hungry,
and then he comes downstairs
and knocks these jars
off of the shelf.
- [Tom] That proves he's hungry.
- My jelly out to do that.
[Joel] Oh, Helga, that tickles.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Hey, it's
the title character.
- Cleaning after this kid, god.
- [Crow] I recognize him.
He used to be with Def Leppard.
- [Tom] Jackson, get
away from that ectoplasm.
- That boy.
Wait'll I get ahold
of him tomorrow.
Why the shower curtain?
- [Crow] That's a good
question for anyone.
- [Tom] (grunting)
Someone better call Madge,
the Palmolive case worker.
- Trouble waking me up in
the middle of the night.
As if I haven't
had enough of it.
(bottle slamming)
Empty.
- [Tom] Good night, sweet troll.
- [Crow] She needs about
150 hours of beauty sleep.
(Joel, Tom, and Crow crying)
- [Crow] Oh no, look out.
(Joel, Tom, and Crow sighing)
- [Tom] They got us on that one.
- [Crow] I knew it was coming.
- [Joel] I can't believe
she's got to do that
scene over again.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] Back into the kitchen.
- [Crow] She forgot to
put her chin hammock on.
Hey, what's that stuff?
- [Tom] It's the nighttime,
coughing, aching,
sneezing, stuffy head, fever,
so you're being chased
by a human hand medicine.
- [Joel] Good.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] You know things are bad
when you keep a liquor
cabinet in your bedroom.
- That oughtta do it.
- [Tom] For a horse.
- [Crow] Oh Helga.
Oh stewardesses.
Me, you, chandelier, swinging.
- [Joel] I can't believe
she's gonna do this scene
one more time.
They used to call
her One Take Sally,
and now, look, nothing.
- [Tom] Let's see, if I
look in the dictionary,
I think that's where
I keep my stash.
- [Joel] Oh, I've seen this.
This is when she does her
Judy Garland impression.
(Mrs. Hotchkiss gagging)
- [Tom] What the?
- [Crow] No, I think she's
doing Mrs. Captain Kirk.
(Mrs. Hotchkiss gagging)
- [Tom] Got to find push button.
Must lay down.
Must perform death scene.
- [Crow] Oh, grab your pills.
That'll help.
(dramatic music)
(Mrs. Hotchkiss coughing)
(gun blasting)
- [Joel] Helga?
- Mrs. Hotchkiss?
Mrs. Hotchkiss?
- [Tom] She's a victim
of a Hotchkiss disease.
- [Crow] I bet he's
gonna be all choked up,
now that she's dead.
All choked up, get it?
- [Tom] And now, a really
big hand for the little lady.
Mrs. Hotchkiss, right
here on our very floor.
- [Joel] Rings, fingernails,
clippers, lubriderm lotion?
It can't be.
No.
It's a clue.
- [Tom] Hey, little hand?
Little hand?
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] A big old booger.
- [Joel] This goes in
the jar with the others.
- Operator, get me
the sheriff, quick.
- [Tom] If he's not there,
I'll talk to The Skipper.
(phone ringing)
♪ Shaving, shaving,
la, la, la, la, la ♪
- Who?
Paul?
Paul Lawrence?
Will you stop talking so fast.
I can't understand a
word you're saying.
Stop shouting.
(Tom stammering)
Hotchkiss?
- [Tom] Yes, Mrs. Hotchkiss.
- Now don't touch anything.
- [Tom] I won't, just come.
- I'll be there in five minutes.
- [Tom] Oh hurry, please.
- Paul, I know how you feel son.
- [Tom] No you don't.
- I'll get there
as fast as I can.
- [Crow] He doesn't
know how he feels.
He's never been
attacked by a hand.
He has no idea how he feels.
Look at that boy.
He's got a ball of pain inside.
- Try and raise the
county coroner, Earl.
And call my wife.
Tell her I'm liable
to be up all night.
- [Joel] Oh, we'd
better get out of here.
- [Tom] I'll call his wife.
- Sure thing Ted.
- [Tom] I'll tell
her she's married
to a two bit character actor.
(upbeat music)
(funky music)
- Got to think.
Must get back to Galileo 7.
Lives of 400 crew
members hang in balance.
(Joel grunting)
- Vision fading.
Must cut transponder from wrist.
Fashion crude phaser device
with bed slat and light bulb.
- Must control myself.
Must find pastel
colored native female.
Execute Prime
Directive. (screaming)
- (grunting) Hand's
so young looking.
Mrs. Burg I thought you
were dead. (screaming)
- Throat scratchy.
Hand's so dry can scratch
name into it. (grunting)
- Embarrassing cuticles
on finger nails.
Must utilize emotional
memory and get to.
- Listen, (mumbling),
stop it, stop it.
- Stop?
That was my big scene, Joel.
- Hey, yeah, we were
just getting into it.
- This just isn't working.
I don't know how Shatner
does it week after week.
- I don't know why he does
it or who lets him do it.
- I think we should
just be glad he does it.
(alarm buzzing)
- Oh, we got movie sign!
Let's go!
- [Tom] Must get to theater.
(mysterious music)
- [Joel] That hand killed me.
It was hilarious.
- [Crow] Pretty funny.
- [Tom] We have to play
more games like that.
I like role playing games.
- You know, this book
of lists has everything.
Look at here.
What to do when a rogue
hand kills your land lady.
Roddy McDowell, Milton Berle?
- Operator, I'd like to make
a long distance call, please.
- [Tom] Well, I'll
do what I can.
But I can't promise anything.
You know how things
are. (mumbling)
- Never mind, operator.
Sheriff.
- [Joel] Skipper.
Where's the little
body, little buddy?
- I heard a shot.
I ran down from my room.
I found her like this.
- No signs of a bullet.
- Did you hear anything else,
like a door closing
or somebody running?
- [Crow] Or the sound
of one hand clapping?
- No, nothing.
- Looks like she's
been strangled.
You can see the
marks on her throat.
No doubt about it.
- [Joel] This lamp
has panties on it.
- Now tell me boy.
Did you ever see
this gun before?
- It belongs to Mr. Hotchkiss.
She told me that it
had a hair trigger.
- [Tom] Smells like
a hair trigger.
- Yes, it probably fired
when it fell off the table.
Now I know this is
hard on you, boy,
but anything you can
remember will help.
Anything at all.
Now do you recall,
did she leave any
valuables around the house?
Any sizeable amounts of money?
- [Crow] Nothing that I found
rifling through her stuff.
- Not that I know.
- Well that isn't
the rumor has it.
That is, if you can
believe my wife, Edith.
And you can't always do that.
- [Joel] So then rumor
wouldn't have it.
- That'll probably be Earl.
- Oh, I'll get the door.
- [Tom] Wow.
Psychic.
(Joel, Tom, and Crow meowing)
- That should do the trick.
At least that's what
my wife Edith says,
it usually does for her.
Two of those and a
glass of warm milk
and she's out like a light.
- [Joel] Make sure you
drink it like a raccoon.
- We'll go over the routine
questions in the morning.
Now Paul, just one other thing.
Maybe you don't want to
stay here in the house.
I could drive you
over to my house,
and we'll find you
another place tomorrow.
- [Crow] I've got a
couple of hammocks,
and a sailor's hat
I'd like you to wear.
- No, I'll be all right.
Don't worry about it.
- Soap and water will
take that ink off.
You better go upstairs,
and try and get some sleep.
- [Joel] Strange kid, dipping
his hands in ink like that.
How do you figure.
- All through downstairs then.
- Think you got it (mumbling)?
- Well, most of the
prints were pretty small
They seemed to match the
ones we got off the gun
and the flashlight.
- [Crow] Prince is pretty small.
- Yeah, I think so,
but I can't tell yet.
Oh, there was one that
might be interesting.
Got it off a medallion
she was wearing.
- How soon can we get a report?
- Well, I'll telephoto a
set of these to Washington,
and run a make on 'em here.
We ought to know something
in, oh, five, six hours.
What about the kid?
- Earl I don't know.
I don't like to guess
on a case like this.
I just don't understand why
he wants to stay in the house.
I should think he'd want to
get as far away from here
as possible.
- Ah, he's a medical student.
He's used to being
around dead bodies.
- I suppose.
- [Tom] Just like us.
- Well come on.
We've got a full night's
work ahead of us.
- Yeah, maybe if we're lucky
we'll get an hour of sleep.
(Sheriff laughing)
- [Tom] Yeah, nice improv.
Coconut cream pie, it
just doesn't figure.
That cat is thirsty.
- [Crow] His pants shrunk.
- [Joel] Now to catch a hand,
you've got to think like a hand.
I'll lay out some
press on nails.
Yeah, that would work.
Or maybe some lotion.
Lubriderm or?
Yeah, I know, some
Isotoner gloves.
That would work great.
Oh magic lamp.
Help me find the hand.
- Doctor Weitzberg.
Weitzberg.
- [Joel] Hello, operator, hello.
- Operator, long
distance, please.
- [Joel] Long distance to where?
Where would you like to call to?
- I'd like to call
Doctor Max Weitzberg.
- [Joel] Weitzberg, how
would you spell that?
Washington, D.C.
- No, no, operator, I
don't have the number.
- [Joel] Can you spell the name?
- Listen, operator,
this is an emergency.
- [Joel] It's an emergency?
- No, I'll hold on, okay.
- [Joel] Could you hold on?
How do you spell that name?
- No, Weitzberg.
- [Joel] Weitzberg? (mumbling)
- W.
- [Joel] W.
- E.
- [Joel] W-E.
- I-T-Z.
- [Joel] I-T-Z, gotcha.
- B.
- [Joel] Keep trucking.
- E.
- [Joel] I can hear you,
but you're fading.
Are you on drugs?
Would you like to
call the drug hotline?
Are you tripping?
Be on the lookout
for a crawling hand.
Crawls up on the banister,
and then drops on people.
Are you sure you can
hold on the line?
(dramatic music)
Hello, I can't hear you.
It tends to drop on people
right when they are
about to pass out.
(Tom groaning)
- [Crow] Wow!
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] This is action packed.
(Paul screaming)
- [Crow] Come on, spit it out.
Cough it up.
(siren blaring)
First word.
Sounds like smoke.
(Paul grunting)
- [Joel] Cootchie
cootchie cootchie.
Cootchie cootchie coo.
Playdough face.
(Joel mumbling)
Did he just give
him a wet willie?
- [Tom] I think he did.
With his own saliva,
pretty tricky.
- Boy, I sure could use a beer.
- Who couldn't, but
we can't stop now.
- Bet there's some
in the kitchen.
- Not me, not here.
- [Tom] Me neither.
- A nice cool beer.
- [Tom] A tall, frosty one.
- Hundreds of miles away by now.
Just think of that
long, tall, foamy brew.
- [Joel] Yowser.
- You could talk a
snake out of his skin.
Okay, let's take a look.
With my luck she
won't even have any.
- Dames like her always
keep beer around.
- [Joel] Always.
- I told you there'll be
beer in the refrigerator.
Holy!
Come here!
- What's the matter?
- [Tom] It's a two
for one special.
- I don't know, but I'm
getting out of here.
- [Crow] It's a body, dummy.
- Wait a minute, he
might still be alive.
- [Tom] No, it's not
a dummy, it's a body.
- Listen, buddy, we were
supposed to collect the dame,
and that's all.
This guy's on his own.
- He is alive.
Let's get him out of here.
- [Tom] You know, it doesn't
get any better than this.
(siren blaring)
- [Joel] You spend a
hard day loading bodies,
and you got one more
than you bargained for.
It's Miller time.
- [Tom] (mumbling) I was
making a long distance call,
and then, all I remember is.
(Paul screaming)
I slept with that!
- [Crow] Wow, he really musta
had his beer goggles on.
(Paul screaming)
(tires screeching)
- [Joel] Oh, he's high.
- [Tom] There goes the deposit.
- [Crow] This happens every
time you work with a live one.
- Of course I don't believe it.
Who could?
And don't think I'm gonna
let some fantastic story
about a ghost, fingerprints
or no fingerprints,
stop me from carrying
out this project.
- Oh now wait a minute.
- I'm not waiting for anything.
- [Tom] Calm down, Bucky.
- I was given a goal
and a time limit,
and that time limit
has just about run out.
- Lee, I think we're forgetting
the facts of the situation.
I know it all may
sound rather trivial,
with all of your problems here,
but the fact of
the matter remains
that a murder has
been committed.
And the prime
suspect in this case
happens to be one of our men.
- [Tom] This was no
suicide, it was murder.
- I gather from the attitude
of Mr, Mydell of security,
that it won't be long before
he applies real pressure
right here.
We may find ourselves
right in the middle
of an investigation.
- However, you do have
an alternative, Lee.
When Mydell calls,
you can gain time
by simply stating that
Lockhart had no authorization
to be in California,
and at the present time
you haven't the slightest
idea where he is.
An absolutely true statement.
One which you can't
possibly be criticized for.
- [Tom] Unless you
flub your lines.
- Even I could fly to Palms,
and investigate
this ghost story.
It may hold up the
project a couple of days,
practically nothing to lose.
- Well, what do you say?
- [Joel] It's tempting.
(phone ringing)
- All right, you win.
Go on, take off.
- [Tom] Now we got to
work on those O rings.
- Berringer speaking.
- [Joel] Yeah, hi, are you
wearing rubber underwear?
- Yes, Mr. Mydell.
(plane engines roaring)
- [Tom] Bye.
- [Crow] Got to think.
Must think.
Must find hand.
Must comb hair.
Must get vitales,
rub into scalp.
Get rid of flaking.
- Paul?
- [Tom] Little buddy.
- Sheriff.
- You all right?
- Sure.
- Where have you been?
- [Joel] Out by the lagoon.
- I just took a walk.
I woke up.
I guess this thing bothered me
a little more than I thought.
I just took a walk.
- But you're filthy dirty.
- [Tom] Yeah, and
you're stocky, tubby.
- And you're all sweaty.
You must've walked awfully hard.
Now look, Paul, I'm here
because an ambulance driver
called me.
He told me a strange
kind of a story.
Have you got
anything to tell me?
- [Crow] Just a strange
kind of a story.
- No sir.
- All right, I'll tell
you what I want you to do.
I want you to stick
close to house.
Now, I wouldn't go out
at all if I were you.
I don't care what you do,
but stick close to house.
Do you understand?
- Oh, why don't you
go ahead and arrest me
and get it over with.
- There's no charge
against you boy.
Not yet.
- [Tom] I'm not
a boy, I'm a man.
- Now I suggest you go
up and get some sleep.
You've had a hard night.
- [Crow] Hard day's night.
- Yes sir.
(Joel, Tom, Crow groaning)
- [Tom] Hi, welcome
to your room.
- [Joel] He's a
rebel without a hand.
(car starting)
- [Tom] Dear Kitty,
by the time you hear
this, I'll be dead.
- [Joel] Good
morning, Mr. Phelps.
- I'm telling this,
really, for you.
(dramatic music)
Mr. Farnstrom and Marta.
- [Crow] I would now like
to sing, Cathy's Clown.
- I know you will both realize
that it is the truth.
- [Tom] I have touched
the unclean thing.
- You were right, Professor.
- [Joel] Dogs can fly.
- [Crow] Cold fusion
is impossible.
- Keep things to myself.
I tried to be a lone wolf.
- [Tom] Now I'm a dead duck.
- I guess I wanted all
the credit for myself.
Marta and I were swimming.
And up on the sand we found
something quite interesting.
It was Lock's.
Just an arm.
Had a strange covering.
I guessed right away it
must've been (mumbling).
- [Tom] Tripping.
- [Joel] Remind me not to
drop acid after school.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] He's doing his
Pete Townsend impression.
There it is.
People try to put us down.
- [Joel] It's a close
and play phonograph.
- [Crow] Drop it.
- [Tom] Stomps.
Close it.
Shatters.
Step on it.
Smashes.
- [Crow] Hey, it's
Timothy Hutton.
- [Joel] No, it's more
like Adam Ant to me.
- [Crow] Maybe.
- [Tom] It's from a place
called unchartered desert isle.
- [Crow] Dear Skipper,
why haven't you sent help?
Signed, The Castaways.
- When'd this
thing arrive, Earl?
- [Earl] Why, what is it?
- It's from Washington.
We asked for a confirmation
on those fingerprints
at the Hotchkiss house.
Well, they said they belong
to a guy I never heard of,
Lockhart.
- Who?
- Melvin Lockhart.
Do you know a Melvin Lockhart?
- [Joel] June's boy?
- Anybody in this
town by that name?
- Never heard of one.
- [Joel] June's boy?
- That isn't the half of it.
They're moving in.
- Who's moving in?
- Washington.
- [Joel] June's boy.
George?
Grover?
- Great Caesar's ghost.
- [Crow] Julius?
Augustus?
- Can you tell me why they
want in on a case like this?
- [Joel] Curiosity?
Money?
- A widow lady gets
herself killed.
A prime suspect, the
only possible suspect,
I've got right here in my hands.
(Joel, Tom, and Crow moaning)
I'm gonna make an arrest
within a couple hours.
- The kid?
- Most certainly the kid.
You know the way
he's been acting.
- [Crow] Like us, bad.
- He's the only one who
could possibly have done it.
Now they come up with
a man named Lockhart.
- [Tom] June's boy.
- And they're taking over.
Earl, I'll tell you
what's happened.
They've got so many
fingerprints in Washington,
they've got 'em all mixed up.
Well, what's the use.
We can't buck 'em, not yet.
(Joel, Tom, and Crow grunting,
coughing, and whistling)
They also want to have us
put a guard on the house.
Nobody gets in.
- Want me to go over
and sit on the place.
- Yeah, you better.
- [Tom] Better bring a cushion.
- While you're there, keep
an eye on young Lawrence.
I suppose I should've picked
him up long before this,
but I just didn't want
him to have a record
until I was 100% sure.
- [Joel] He's such a sweet kid.
- And then after
those Washington boys
get through fooling around,
I'm afraid he's
still gonna be it,
and I'd bet a hundred
dollars on it.
- Okay, I'll get
right over there.
- All right.
- [Crow] Damn MaryAnn.
(upbeat music)
- [Tom] Clearasil.
Clearasil.
Oxy, Oxy.
- Yes, what can I do for you?
- Afternoon, Sheriff,
I'm Steve Curan,
this is Doc Weitzberg, and
we're from Washington, D.C.
- [Joel] We talk real fast.
- Well, you government
boys really work fast.
You got here in a hurry.
Let me get you some coffee.
- Well, thank you, no.
- No thank you.
- Say tell me, who's
this man Lockhart?
- Wait a minute, let's
not get started off
on the wrong foot here, Sheriff.
- Yeah, I know, you ask
the questions, I don't.
Well you boys are from
the bureau, aren't you?
- Well that's just it, Sheriff,
we're from Space Operations.
- Space Operations?
Oh now, wait a minute boys.
This is Palms, California,
population 2306.
- [Joel] We don't
have space here.
- We know all about
that, Sheriff.
We just want to ask you
a few questions is all.
- About this very man, Lockhart.
Has he been seen?
- Well, I don't know who you
boys are, or why you're here.
As far as I'm concerned,
you've got no authority at all
to ask me questions.
- Now wait a minute,
we didn't come out here
to get pushed around.
- Now, Steve, just a minute.
Sheriff, as a matter of fact,
all we want is your permission
to go through the house.
- Nobody goes through the house.
Not til the boys from
the Bureau get here.
And I've got an armed guard
that says nobody does.
- [Joel] Yowser.
- [Tom] Oh yeah, well
we know Buzz Aldrin.
- [Crow] Fatty.
(Crow grunting)
Oh, that's not so bad.
I don't really have acne anyway.
I can go to that dance.
It's not a pimple, it's my nose.
What was I thinking of?
- [Joel] Hubcap, duck.
- Oh, we just talked
to the sheriff.
- Yeah, he called me.
- He didn't change
his mind, did he?
- Nope.
- Well, do you mind if we
just look around outside?
- Nothing to see,
but help yourself.
- Do you have any theories?
- Yeah, somebody killed her.
That's my theory.
- [Tom] Norman, get away
from the window, Norman.
- Well, Steve, I guess we
might as well be on our way.
- Doc, you notice,
they don't build houses
like this anymore.
- [Crow] Kick Sheriff.
Kick him.
- Oh no, they sure
don't, do they.
- [Tom] No they don't make
houses like this anymore.
(Tom grunting)
- Well, we'll see you around.
- See ya later.
- Yeah.
- [Tom] Good bye.
(car starting)
- [Joel] Your muffler.
- [Tom] Rapunzel, Rapunzel,
let down your hand.
- [Crow] Yeah, I think they're
gonna do a scene from Cyrano.
- Whatever we gotta get done,
we better get done fast.
That cold fish could be
around here any second.
- [Crow] Hey, I think somebody
just called me a cold fish.
Why?
- Did you distinguish whether
it was a man or woman?
- It was a pretty
quick glance, Doc.
I'm not sure.
- Look Steve.
- [Tom] Incoming, duck.
- [Joel] Now the
gates over here.
Hey, how'd you get over there?
Geez, ow, down there.
Could you get that for me?
- It's a note.
Come back tonight, after dark.
- Back door'll be unlocked.
I have something
important to tell you.
- [Tom] Wear something sheer.
- No signature.
- Well, I didn't
have a date tonight.
Did you?
- Well, it looks like we
both have now, doesn't it?
- [Crow] Let's see,
something sheer.
How about that pink
chiffon number.
Oh no wait, you're using that.
What about that taffeta,
that tea length,
you know, the one I wore
to the IGY convention.
You know, the night I went
home with Eureka Garren.
You remember?
(car starting)
- Hey.
- [Joel] Hey, wait a minute,
stop or I'll say hey again.
Ouch.
- Paul?
- [Tom] How'd she get in?
- [Crow] She found the hole
in the security curtain.
- [Tom] Paul?
- Paul.
- What are you doing here?
Get out.
- Paul, are you all right?
I read in the paper about
poor Mrs. Hotchkiss.
It's such a terrible thing.
- Never mind.
Get out of here.
- Paul, that thing on the beach.
I just can't get
it out of my mind.
- [Tom] Well I can't
get it out of my house.
- No.
Get out.
- Why are you staying here?
It's no good.
You can come to our house.
- Marta, please.
- Marta, what are
you doing here?
- Harrison, get her
out of this house!
Just get her out!
- You just get
back to your room.
- [Tom] And no playing
with your hand,
and no supper.
- Wait a minute.
I've a right to see Paul.
I'm a friend of his.
- Get her out of this house.
- [Crow] I think he wants
her out of the house.
- Come on, Marta, out, come on.
- [Tom] Bye Marta.
- And don't let her come back!
- [Joel] Think he's been
watching James Dean movies,
you guys?
What is that?
An ice cream place?
- [Tom] Coffee house, I think.
- [Crow] Bagel shop.
- [Joel] Pizza place.
- [Tom] Oh, no, it's a mortuary.
Silly us.
- [Crow] Why didn't they say?
- [Joel] Is that a peace sign?
- [Tom] Nope, I hope
this movie's over soon.
- I didn't know she had any
relatives back east at all.
I know she used to
speak of an uncle,
but he was in England
or some place.
Where'd you say you
were from again?
- Pennsylvania.
- New York.
- Oh, he's from New York.
- And he's from Pennsylvania.
We heard about the
tragedy, and flew out here.
- I see.
Well, here she is.
You can take a look if you like.
Really looks very well.
Of course, we got the body
quite soon after the crime.
And there weren't any marks,
except the ones on her throat.
- [Tom] And the ones we added.
- You know, sometimes
in cases like this.
- [Crow] We put
turtlenecks on 'em.
- Looks very well, I think.
- Yes, Steve, yes.
- What's he doing?
What is that thing?
- [Joel] It's a dust buster.
- Wards off evil spirits.
- Oh, I see.
- There's absolutely no doubt.
Thanks very much,
we're satisfied.
- And you're absolutely
right, she looks very well.
- [Crow] Which is more than
I can say for you, baldy.
- [Tom] Hey, come back.
Is that really a dust buster?
(dramatic music)
- Hello?
- [Tom] Hi.
- Hello.
- Anybody here?
- [Joel] Yeah,
us, we're in here.
- It looks like we're alone.
- [Crow] At last.
- I wonder where our
little friend is.
- [Joel] He's right here.
- If he was watching, all right,
he'll be down any minute.
- [Tom] I'll be
your little friend.
Oh, it's the crawling bladder.
- If we could only
turn on a light.
- [Joel] These guys are
the greatest comedy team
since Willie Aames
and Scott Baio.
- We gotta keep this flashlight
out of the windowsill.
Steve.
- What?
- Give me the light.
Put it on the gauge.
- What do you see?
- Well there's an indication.
It's faint, but it's definite.
- [Joel] This corn
relish is radio active.
- Steve, keep it over here.
- What's it reading?
- This is very strange.
- What's that?
- Well there's a very
strong reading right here,
on top of the shelf.
Nothing above or below.
- That's ridiculous, Doc.
No man could be
up on that shelf.
It would never hold him.
- [Tom] Just part
of a man, maybe.
Just a hunch.
- Lockhart's
fingerprints, remember.
- Well perhaps we
could trace the trail
back to where it come from.
- Keep the light on the gauge.
- [Crow] Hey, who are
they trying to fool
with that stud finder.
- Steve.
- [Tom] Hey, they
haven't found me yet.
(Tom mumbling)
- [Crow] Oh brother.
- Steve.
It's on the ceiling.
- Now Doc, what man
do you happen to know
that walks on a ceiling.
- [Joel] Lionel Ritchie?
- Turn off the light.
- All right, let him move first.
Hello.
Come on, say something.
- [Tom] Hey, if you
can't say anything nice,
just don't say anything at all.
- [Crow] It's an Elvis zombie.
- [Tom] Thank you,
thank you very much.
Priscilla, make me
a banana sandwich.
- [Joel] Check out those classic
Elvis karate moves there.
- [Crow] Like from Blue Hawaii.
- [Tom] Ladies and Gentlemen,
Elvis has left the kitchen.
(dramatic music)
Good night, everybody.
- [Earl] Back of the house.
Come on.
Back up.
- [Joel] They're in the house.
- What are you two
doing back here?
- Well don't bother about us,
go after that maniac.
- Well now, you
must've seen him.
- [Tom] The guy
in the rhinestone.
- He ran right past you.
- I don't know what
you're talking about.
Into the house, I'll
call the sheriff.
- Look, officer,
you're wasting time.
Go after that man.
- Shut up, and get
back into the house.
- It's all right, Doc.
There's nothing we can
do about it right now.
- [Tom] Into the house.
- [Crow] Why you lily-livered,
flea-bitten federal boys.
- [Tom] He's got the
eye of the beast.
- [Joel] You know, if he
sings Maria right now,
I'm gonna lose it, you guys.
- [Crow] No, he won't sing it.
He's not even
sporting a dance belt.
Or dancing a sport belt.
- [Tom] No zombies, not
allowed, no zombies.
- [Joel] No strangling,
not allowed.
- [Crow] No lights.
- [Tom] Music's cool though.
(dramatic music)
- [Crow] Boy, you get a zombie
on the business end of a mop
and there's no telling
what's gonna happen.
- [Tom] Murder's the word,
word, word, word, word.
Murder's the word,
- [Joel and Tom]
murder's the word.
We got a new dance, and
it goes the like this.
- [Tom] Murder's the word,
word, word, word, word.
- [Joel] Well you shake bub
up at the end of your hand.
- [Tom] It goes like this.
The kid who kills Hotchkiss.
- [Crow] I said no killing.
- [Tom] Oh, it's that rat boy.
- [Joel] I guess a
double scoop sundae's
out of the question now.
Oh, we got to get out of here.
(mysterious music)
- You know, that
hand's not so tough.
What's the worst thing he's
gonna do to you, anyway?
Pinch you?
- Yeah, and how does he
know how to go after you?
He's got no brain
and no leverage.
- Hey, what are you
guys talking about?
- Oh, we're just mocking
this week's monster.
I mean what's a hand
gonna do to you, anyway?
- Well, there's a lot of
things a hand could do
if you stop to think about it.
Like if you're sleeping, comes
up with these two fingers,
shoves 'em up your
nose, you suffocate.
Stone dead.
- I hardly think
that's possible.
- Or, you could use this finger,
and come up beside
somebody and tap 'em.
Whiplash, dead.
- Oh yeah, right, I bet.
- Well, and who knows what else.
It's like, he could
do this thing.
Like that.
You look down, til
you're bored to death.
Or something like that.
- Yeah right, Joel,
tell me about it.
- Or, let's say he had
an accomplice hand,
who is friend, and
they gang up on you,
and give you an
Indian rub, like that.
- Right, Joel, sure,
tell us about it.
- I can't believe
you guys don't know.
Then there's the cuff, chuck,
gnaw, nor, grap, peck, fleck.
- Geez, oh yeah.
- Right.
- I don't think that hand
could scare me anyway.
Free roaming, rogue,
disconnected glove,
even if it were
connected to a forearm
it wouldn't bother me.
Tickle you to death?
Sure.
But scary?
I know a hand with callouses
the size of a football,
but it didn't scare
me in the least.
Joel, remember the?
Joel?
(Crow screaming)
(upbeat music)
- Oh, I know I'll never
remember this stuff.
Ibsen, O'Neill.
- Joel, Joel, it was horrible.
There's this big
hand chasing me.
- Do you understand it, Marta?
- [Tom] We got him.
- [Joel] Crow, we
were teasing you.
That was Gypsy in a
giant hand costume.
- [Tom] We skanked you.
- [Crow] Oh, I knew that?
- [Tom] Watch the movie.
- Kid,
that exam's tomorrow,
you've got to pass.
Well, you know they
expect twice as much
from foreign students.
- [Tom] You know the boys do.
- Oh, I wasn't asleep.
It's just that.
- I know, you're
concerned about Paul.
He'll be okay.
- Oh, Patsy, I just
don't understand it.
What's happened to him?
It was terrible.
- [Joel] Well, it's time she
explained puberty to you.
- He screamed at me,
and why is he staying
in that house?
- Gee, I don't know.
Papa hasn't said a
word about it at home.
Well, there's no
use me asking him.
He just won't tell me anything
about stuff like that.
- They're keeping
him a prisoner.
- Well, he may be a suspect.
- Paul didn't kill anyone.
- [Tom] He's Paul.
- That I'm sure of.
- Pop always says
you can't be sure what
anyone is going to do.
In certain circumstances.
- [Tom] Yeah, but your dad
was in Gilligan's Island.
- He didn't kill anyone.
I'm sure of that.
- [Crow] Oh, he may choke the
heck out of people at times,
but kill, nah.
- I thought it's perhaps
time for a little rest
and refreshment.
You know, studying at
such a furious pace,
without pause, can
be very exhausting.
- I'm afraid that's
not the case.
- [Tom] Grandpa Ed.
- Not for me.
- No?
In any case, there are
sandwiches and coke,
and I've made quite a
tempting little snack.
- Oh, you sold me, Professor.
Lead the way.
- [Tom] Wow, you
mention h'ordeuvres,
and the babes go wild.
- I'm really not hungry.
- [Joel] That's all right,
I'm really not your grandpa.
- And I'd better
start, I'm afraid,
if I don't want
to flunk tomorrow.
- Oh well, as you wish.
Patsy and I will have to
eat extra portions then.
- [Crow] Yeah, and Patsy can
really tuck away the chow.
- Be back in a few minutes, pal.
- [Tom] Wow, look,
she really is smart.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Hey.
That looks like Roland Gift
from Fine Young Cannibals.
- [Tom] Hi, I'm Roland Gift
from the Fine Young Cannibals.
(Paul tapping on window)
(dramatic music)
You drive me crazy.
- Paul.
- Could I talk to
you for a minute?
- Yes, of course, come inside.
- [Tom] It's about your stairs.
There are none.
- Paul, I've been so worried.
- I know.
Listen, I'm going away.
- Away?
- [Joel] Away, you
know, not here.
- Now.
Just as soon as I
get rid of something
that must be destroyed.
- [Crow] His plantar's warts?
- I just couldn't go without
saying goodbye first.
- Paul, what's the matter?
What are you afraid oF?
Tell me.
- [Tom] The dark?
Well, no, not the dark.
- I can't.
There's just one thing
I want to tell you.
I didn't kill Mrs. Hotchkiss.
- Oh, I know that Paul.
You couldn't have.
- But there are people
who think I did.
Sheriff Townsend.
- Pete Townsend, John
Enwhistle, the list goes on.
- Everything will be all right.
- [Crow] He looks
like Bob Crane.
- Grandfather will help you.
He loves you very much, Paul.
- Don't touch me.
Listen, I can't explain it,
but I'm all mixed up.
And there's something terrible
that's happened to me,
and there's only person
that I could've relied on
in this world,
and I almost killed
him a few minutes ago.
- What do you mean?
- Never mind.
It would take too
long to explain.
I don't have the time.
- [Tom] Or the
communication skills.
- There are times when I'm
all right, and then I'm not,
and then when I'm
myself, and then I'm not.
And the periods when I'm
myself are getting shorter
and shorter.
Do you understand?
- No.
- Well then don't try.
- [Tom] She doesn't
understand much, really.
She is very smart.
- No Paul, I'm not
gonna let you go.
If you're ill, we'll help you.
You can come and stay with us,
and we'll take care of
you until you're well.
- [Tom] I'm not moving in here
until you get some front stairs.
- Do you remember when you
asked me that question?
Whether I was going back
home after summer was over.
I was only teasing you.
I never meant to go.
I want to stay here.
I want to be here with you.
I love you, Paul.
- No, Marta, you
don't understand.
- No, I won't let you run away.
- No.
No.
Get away from me.
- [Crow] Joel, I smell a big,
juicy transformation scene
coming up here.
- [Joel] Yeah.
His neck is stiff, for
God's sake, leave him alone.
- What is it?
What's the matter with you?
(Marta screaming)
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Hey, it's Sid Vicious.
- [Tom] That was rotten, Johnny.
- [Joel] And she's Nancy.
And that looks a lot
like the Chelsea Hotel.
- [Grandpa] Marta.
- [Crow] He's the
least successful
strangler in the movies.
He runs around the countryside
giving people Dutch rubs.
(siren blaring)
- [Tom] That's when
a siren was a siren.
Headlights were headlights.
- [Crow] Hats were hats.
- You should've listened to me.
We had no idea.
- [Joel] Heavies were heavy.
- You two should've
thought of that
when you helped him escape.
- [Tom] And sheep
roamed the countryside.
- Both of you.
- Be reasonable now.
- Look, if he does any harm
to that Farnstrom girl,
I'll show you how
unreasonable I can be.
- [Tom] Then I'm gonna whack
you with my sailor hat.
- My daughter's at the
Farnstrom place too.
(tires screeching)
(Marta crying)
- [Crow] Just pull
your hands away.
- Paul's hands.
Why, it was horrible.
- [Tom] 1313 Mockingbird Lane.
This is the place, all right.
- [Joel] Every time
I get a boyfriend,
he crushes my wind pipe.
I don't get it.
- May I speak with
her, Professor?
- [Crow] Sure, Skipper.
- Marta, is was Paul
Lawrence, wasn't it?
- [Joel] One long biscuit
for yes, two for no.
- Paul?
No, not really Paul.
- [Tom] Not Paul, but an
incredible simulation.
- It was in the sand.
It was an arm.
Lying in the sand.
A human arm.
- [Tom] Just speak it.
(Joel, Tom, and Crow crying)
You drive me crazy.
(dramatic music)
The crawling torso.
- It was Paul
Lawrence, wasn't it?
- [Crow] Can't he
ever use the stairs?
(cat meowing)
- [Tom] He's a welcome cat now.
- [Joel] Poor, screwed up kid.
- [Tom] Poor, screwed up cat.
- [Joel] Hey, little hand.
Where are you, buddy?
Oh that's a dust
bunny, that's no good.
There's latex hand,
I found my carmex,
there's some sand in it though.
- [Crow] Let's see, if I were
an arm, where would I hide?
My sleeve, of course. (laughing)
No, maybe the meat freezer.
Yeah.
(dramatic music)
- [Joel] Cage match.
- [Tom] Arm wrestling.
- [Joel] His bag for the arm.
- [Tom] Hey, you're not gonna
wash that with the whites,
are you?
- [Joel] Quick, throw him
in the trash compactor.
Set it on mulch.
- [Tom] Quickest way to turn
a big hand into a little hand.
- [Crow] Nice hand off.
- [Joel] Is he gonna use
that to signal turns now?
(tires screeching)
- [Crow] Here comes the
long arm of the law.
- Hey, his car's gone.
It was parked right
there at the curb.
- Put a call out on the car.
I'll make a double check inside.
- Unit One to Control.
- [Crow] Everything
seems to be in order
in the old woman's room.
- [Tom] Except there's
no old woman here.
- [Crow] Well, you can't
just leave 'em lying around.
- Paul?
- [Joel] George, or John, Ringo?
Who am I kidding?
They'll never get
back together again.
- [Announcer] 39A, code seven.
- Spotted him, heading
down the county dump road,
but he gave him the slip.
- Well, you stay close to
the house, just in case.
We'll check with you later.
- [Tom] This guy
has the worst job,
just staying around the house.
Day after day,
night after night.
- [Crow] One Adam 12,
see the appendage,
corner of Druckster and Main.
Be advised, he's
arm and dangerous.
(upbeat music)
(siren blaring)
- [Tom] Traveling in the woody.
- [Joel] Taking
the world by storm.
(tires screeching)
Oh man, he's gonna soil
that kid's stadium blanket.
(siren blaring)
(tires screeching)
- [Tom] Hey, signal those turns.
- [Crow] That hand
should moisturize more.
That could be eczema (mumbling).
(siren blaring)
Psoriasis.
- [Joel] Itsy bitsy spider
went up the water spout.
Then came the rain, and
washed the spider out.
- [Crow] What's bugging
that hand, anyway?
- [Joel] He's got
a personal vendetta
against anyone with a full body.
- [Tom] You got to
hand it to him though.
- [Joel] Oh you.
- [Crow] That limb's revolting.
(dramatic music)
(tires screeching)
- [Tom] Hey, I'm
trying to drive.
- [Joel] See, now
that's the kind of thing
I'm talking about.
You can tell it's
a low budget movie
because they can't
wreck the car.
See?
- [Tom] Good point.
The crawling hand.
You will believe
a hand can crawl.
That's the Australian
crawl, I think.
- [Crow] You will believe
Alan Hale can act.
- [Tom] No.
- [Crow] Sleeveless.
(dramatic music)
- [Tom] This is all sort
of a hand jives, isn't it?
- [Joel] Yep.
- [Tom] I was born to hand jive.
- [Crow] Whoa, outflanked him.
- [Joel] That's got to hurt.
(Tom grunting)
- [Crow] Hey, hand
to hand combat.
- [Joel] Yeah, now tell that
to the rest of your body.
(cat meowing)
(siren blaring)
- [Tom] Here they
come to save the day.
- [Crow] The cops'll handle it.
- [Tom] Get a grip
on yourself, Crow.
- [Announcer] 39A, clear.
(dramatic music)
- What's this?
- Metallic cloth, it looks like.
- I've never seen
anything like that.
- [Crow] What, have you been
stranded on a desert isle?
- Space travel.
- [Announcer] There's a
prowler at the rear door.
- Lockhart's, I can bet my life.
- [Tom] You might have to.
- Let's look around this way.
- There he is.
- [Tom] And he's looking good.
- Wait, you're not gonna
gun him down, are you?
- He's a killer.
If he doesn't come quietly,
I'll have to shoot him.
- [Curan] But he's just a kid!
- Sure he's just a kid.
I know all about kids like him.
The county jail is full of 'em.
- [Crow] Sal Mineo
impersonators?
- Paul, don't do
anything foolish.
- That's right, Paul.
I don't want to hurt you.
Now put that bottle down,
and come over here quietly.
- [Tom] Put that bottle down.
- Come on now, boy.
I wouldn't want to use this gun.
Now put the bottle down so
we can get back into town.
Paul, listen to me.
You didn't hurt her.
- [Joel] Think, Paul, think.
(cats meowing)
- [Tom] Cat fight.
- [Joel] Cats can't
resist the cosmic treat.
- [Tom] Right out of his hand.
- [Joel] A beefy,
moist meal in a sleeve.
- Are you gonna put
that bottle down
or am I gonna have to
take it away from you.
- [Tom] Think about it, Paul.
- [Crow] They're
living hand to mouth.
- [Tom] Not a lot
of meat on a hand,
but if you cook it
right, it's good eating.
- [Crow] I like buffalo
astronaut arms, myself.
(cats meowing)
- [Tom] It's amazing that a
disembodied hand still bleeds
with no blood
pressure or anything.
- [Crow] Knuckle sandwich.
- [Tom] Nice swoon.
- [Crow] Good form.
- [Tom] Came out of his
tuck and everything.
- We better get him to
a hospital right away.
- [Tom] This hand isn't
crawling anywhere.
(Tom gasping)
- Doc!
Doc, come over here.
- [Tom] Hey, don't
leave me with the kid.
This was no boating accident.
- Fingerprints don't lie.
- [Joel] I'm here Steve.
- [Announcer] 34, clear.
- Okay, you two, let's go.
- [Joel] Hey, whatcha
looking for, fatty?
- Not a trace.
Not a solitary trace.
- [Joel] Must be a talent meter.
- There's my boy.
Just hypertension now
What you had is an
entirely different matter.
We'll talk about it
when you get well.
- What I had.
What happened to it?
- Let's just say
that life can exist
under different temperatures,
and a fever of 104 was
enough to finish it off.
Fortunately for you, and for us.
- I just talked to Berringer.
He wants to see it immediately.
- Good, I'm glad he does.
The sooner we get
rid of it, the better
Oh, Marta, come on in.
- Is it all right?
- For a little while.
I think it'll do him
more good than harm.
Excuse me.
- [Tom] I think so too.
- Are you sure you
got that thing fixed
so it won't ever get away again?
- Don't worry about it, Sheriff.
It's in a metal box,
and it's locked,
and in about two minutes
it's gonna be on an airplane,
and no one will
ever see it again.
- [Tom] Unless the weather
starts getting rough.
- [Crow] Well, I'm on my
way for a three hour tour.
- Come on, tell me,
did you mean what
you said last night,
about staying here?
- [Tom] Yes, I intend not to.
- I don't play games.
Too weak.
- How can I help myself?
You know women can't
resist weak men.
- Then you're gonna stay?
- [Tom] Or the rich
taste of smores.
- Just wait til I
get out of this bed.
Just you.
- [Tom] And me,
and my extra arm.
- [Crow] Oh no,
not these two guys.
- [Joel] Man, they
couldn't even work
for Domino's pizza delivery.
- [Tom] About time
for a tall cool one.
A couple of road sodas.
- Wonder what all the
secrecy's about this time.
- There you go, sticking
your nose into something
that's none of your business.
All we're supposed to do is
deliver it to the airport.
- Yeah, but those people
inside got me curious.
You know that fella
from Washington,
the way he kept looking at it,
asking me if I was
sure it was locked.
I'd give anything to
take a look inside.
- Not me, I don't
care what's in it.
Come on, let's get moving.
- That's your
trouble. No curiosity.
You will never get any
place without curiosity.
You gotta find out about things.
- Yeah, well I like it that way.
- What harm would it
do to take a look?
I've got the key.
- It might be dangerous.
- What do you think, it's alive?
You don't see any
holes in the box.
You think it'll bite
you or something?
- [Tom] Way to go, Mr. Logic.
- Always talking me into doing
something I don't want to do.
- Have I ever steered you wrong?
- [Tom] Well, there's
that whole beer,
dead body thing, yeah.
- [Crow] No, don't do it guys.
- [Tom] We better
get out of here.
Here, come on.
- [Joel] Don't do it!
- [Tom] Let's go, you guys.
(Crow screaming)
- [Crow] Next time
use Federal Express.
Or maybe hand delivery.
(dramatic music)
♪ Mockingbird ♪
♪ Bird's the word ♪
♪ Bird, bird's the word ♪
(mysterious music)
- Okay, you guys, that's
the end of the movie.
We made it.
And this is time for
the Ram Chip episode,
where you say a good
thing about the film,
and a bad thing,
you get a ram chip.
Ready, go ahead Crow.
- Well, let's see.
The good thing was
those cats showed us
a new definition for
finger food. (laughing)
- And the bad thing?
- Bad thing was, well,
never trust a deliveryman.
- Okay, here's your ram chip.
There you go.
Now, Tom Servo.
- Okay, the good thing was
there was a Swedish babe
in the film, who
didn't get killed.
- Yeah, and the bad thing.
- She didn't spend the time
on her makeup that it deserved
as the film went on.
- Okay, here's
your ram chip, pal.
There you go.
All right.
Well, we want to thank
everybody who's been writing in,
and I want to thank
the mad scientists
for faxing the
letters back up to me.
But anyway, this one's from
Ricky Fowls, and he says,
he wrote some letters, and
this one's to you, Crow.
He goes, "Dear Crow.
"I really like you.
"I laugh when you make a joke."
So that's a good thing, right?
- Have I made one yet?
- Yeah.
"And I hope I can
see you someday."
- Take a look, kid.
"And Joel, someday I would
like you to take apart Servo."
- Hey, can I help?
- "And I like Gypsy,
because he looks cool."
Gypsy's a she, by the way.
That's from Ricky Fowls, and
he also did some drawings.
We got those in still
store, don't we Cambot?
Okay, let's take a look at that.
We got one of Crow,
and then it says,
"Look on back."
And you turn it around,
and we got a Tom Servo there.
(robots gushing)
See, isn't that neat?
And then, on the next
one, it says, "Gypsy".
It's like this.
And then it says,
"Look on back."
And it's got Joel.
Right there, see I got a little
light bulb above my head.
'Cause I had a bright idea.
All right, well, read
the address, Crow.
Keep the cards and
letters coming in.
- Can I do it, buddy?
- Servo, read it.
- Tom Servo, read the letter.
- All right, send your letters
to the Mystery Science
Theater Fan Club.
P.O. Box 5325.
Hopkins, Minnesota, 55343.
Send them now.
- Thanks a lot for watching.
Scientists, I hope you're happy.
- Yeah, yeah, I'm happy.
Are you happy, Clyde?
(Clyde grunting)
Tell 'em, are you happy?
Tell 'em.
- Got to reach console.
Got to end experiment.